Register of the Finnish Relief Fund records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Motion Picture Division File, 1940
  - Subject file - Finland Fights
    - Correspondence
      - State chairmen
        - Washington (Folder 24)
        - West Virginia (Folder 25)
        - Wisconsin (Folder 26)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 27)
    - Viewing reports (Folder 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 29)
  - Telegrams (Folder 30)
- Music and Entertainment Division File, 1940
  Mostly correspondence with regional offices, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Correspondence (Box 220)
    - General (Folder 1-3)
    - Regional offices
      - Florida (Folder 4)
      - Maryland - Baltimore (Folder 5)
      - New York State - Rochester (Folder 6)
      - Ohio - Cincinnati (Folder 7)
      - Pennsylvania - Pittsburgh (Folder 8)
  - Subject file (Box 221)
    - General
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Benefit concerts (Folder 2)
      - Musicians (Folder 3)
      - Vocalists (Folder 4)
    - Fashion show, Elizabeth Arden (Folder 5)
    - Help Finland Cabaret at the Waldorf-Astoria (Folder 6)
    - Robert Ripley Program (Folder 7)
- Professional Groups Division File, 1940
  Mostly correspondence relating to activities of lawyers and physicians, arranged alphabetically by profession
  - Accountants (Box 222, Folder 1)
  - Lawyers
    - General. Includes lists of lawyers (Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence
      - General. Includes correspondence with physicians
        - General (Folder 4-5)
        - Atlantic seaboard (Folder 6)
        - Midwest (Folder 7)
        - New England (Folder 8)
        - New York (Folder 9)
        - Pacific (Folder 10)
        - South (Box 223, Folder 1)
      - Davis, William (Folder 2)
      - Fates, H. (Folder 3)
      - Ryan, James (Folder 4)
      - Stinchfield, Frederick (Folder 5)
      - Wardell, Allen (Folder 6)
  - Physicians
    - Acknowledgements (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Kinard, Kerwin (Folder 9)
    - Form letters (Folder 10)
    - Lists of contacts (Folder 11)
  - Religious organizations (Folder 12)
- Radio Division File, 1939-1940
  Announcements, correspondence, memoranda, talks, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence (Box 224)
    - General. Includes correspondence with local chairmen (Folder 1)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 2)
    - Hoover Library, Palo Alto, California. Includes list of Herbert Hoover's radio broadcasts for sale through Library of Voices, Audio-Scriptons, Inc. (Folder 3)
    - New York
      - General (Folder 4-7)
      - New York City (Box 225)
        - General (Folder 1)
        - NBC (Folder 2)
        - WHOM (Folder 3)
        - YMCA (Folder 4)
        - WOR (Folder 5)
  - Memoranda, Inter-office (Folder 6)
  - Spot announcements (Folder 7)
  - Talks
    - General (Folder 8)
    - Five minutes (Folder 9)
    - Fifteen minutes (Folder 10)
- Sport Activities File, 1939-1940
  Correspondence, memoranda, publicity material, reports, speeches, suggestions, telegrams relating mostly to sport events, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Calendar of events (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - General. Includes chairman's reports on activities (Folder 3)
        - A-D (Folder 4)
        - E-K (Folder 5)
        - M-Q (Folder 6)
        - R-W (Folder 7)
      - Acknowledgments (Folder 8)
      - Circular letters (Folder 9)
      - Sports Division letter #9 (Folder 10)
    - Amateur Athletic Union (Box 227, Folder 1)
    - Colleges (Folder 2-3)
    - Individuals
      - Bronson, Jimmie (Folder 4)
      - Fogelson, William E.
        - General (Folder 5)
        - Personal (Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 7)
      - Lucey, John F. (Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 9)
  - Donations (Folder 10)
  - Fundraising file (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda (Folder 2)
  - Office file (Folder 3)
  - Publicity file
    - Clipping (Folder 4)
    - Broadcast (Folder 5)
    - Newspapers (Folder 6)
    - Press releases (Folder 7)
  - Reports from committee chairmen (Folder 8)
  - Speeches. Herbert Hoover's address to Baseball Writers' Association (Folder 9)
  - Subject file. Mostly correspondence
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Fight promoters
      - California
        - Los Angeles (Folder 11)
        - San Francisco (Folder 12)
      - Colorado - Denver (Folder 13)
      - District of Columbia (Folder 14)
      - Idaho - Boise (Folder 15)
      - Illinois - Chicago (Folder 16)
      - Indiana - Indianapolis (Folder 17)
      - Louisiana - New Orleans (Folder 18)
      - Maine - Portland (Folder 19)
      - Maryland - Baltimore (Folder 20)
      - Massachusetts
        - Boston (Folder 21)
        - Holyoke (Folder 22)
      - Minnesota - Minneapolis (Folder 23)
      - Missouri
        - Kansas City (Folder 24)
        - St. Louis (Folder 25)
      - Nebraska - Omaha (Box 229, Folder 1)
      - New Jersey
        - Paterson (Folder 2)
        - Trenton (Folder 3)
      - New York
        - New York (Folder 4)
        - Syracuse (Folder 5)
      - Ohio
        - Canton (Folder 6)
        - Cleveland (Folder 7)
        - Columbus (Folder 8)
        - Youngstown (Folder 9)
      - Pennsylvania
        - Philadelphia (Folder 10)
        - Scranton (Folder 11)
      - Texas
        - Dallas (Folder 12)
        - Houston (Folder 13)
      - Wisconsin - Milwaukee (Folder 14)
    - Special events
      - All Star Baseball Game, Tampa, Florida (Folder 15)
      - Golden Gloves tournaments (Folder 16)
      - Rally, Madison Square Garden (Folder 17)
    - Sport events
      - Aquatics (Folder 18)
      - Badminton (Folder 19)
      - Baseball (Folder 20)
      - Basketball (Folder 21)
      - Boxing (Folder 22)
      - Bowling (Folder 23)
      - Bridge, chess, checkers (Folder 24)
      - Fencing (Folder 25)
      - Fishing (Folder 26)
      - Football (Folder 27)
      - Golf (Box 230, Folder 1)
      - Ice hockey (Folder 2)
      - Horse shows (Folder 3)
      - Polo (Folder 4)
      - Racing (Folder 5)
      - Racquets (Folder 6)
      - Rugby (Folder 7)
      - Rallies (Folder 8)
      - Skating (Folder 9)
      - Skeet shooting (Folder 10)
      - Skiing (Folder 11)
      - Soccer (Folder 12)
      - Softball (Folder 13)
      - Tennis
        - Clippings (Folder 14)
        - Correspondence
          - General (Folder 15)
          - Seari, Helenand (Folder 16)
      - Track and field (Folder 17-18)
      - Track and field (Box 231, Folder 1)
      - Trap shooting (Folder 2)
      - Wrestling (Folder 3)
      - Yachting
        - Correspondence
          - General
            - General (Folder 4)
            - A-C (Folder 5)
            - D-H (Folder 6)
            - I-N (Folder 7)
            - O-Z (Folder 8)
          - Finland, Letters from (Folder 9)
          - Nichols, George (Folder 10)
          - Williams, Joe (Folder 11)
        - Form letters (Folder 12)
        - Invoices (Folder 13)
        - Lists of members and clubs (Folder 14)
        - Memoranda (Box 232, Folder 1)
        - Telegrams (Folder 2)
  - Suggestions (Folder 3)
  - Telegrams
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Individuals (A-Z) (Folder 5-27)
- Stage Activities Division File, 1940
  Letters and telegrams, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Fundraising file - "Bridge to Finland" campaign (Box 233, Folder 1)
  - Telegrams (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
- Women's Division File, 1939-1940
  Correspondence, financial reports, form letters, memoranda, reports, telegrams, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Correspondence
    - General, mostly with women's clubs
      - A (Box 233, Folder 4)
      - B (Folder 5)
      - C-G (Folder 6)
      - H-L (Folder 7)
      - M-N (Folder 8)
      - O-P (Folder 9)
      - Q-S (Folder 10)
      - T-Z (Box 234, Folder 1)
    - Pentland, Mary
      - Fundraising files (Folder 2)
      - Letters of thanks (Folder 3)
    - State chairmen (Folder 4)
    - New York business and professional women's clubs (Folder 5)
  - Donation file (Folder 6)
  - Financial reports (Folder 7)
  - Form letters (Folder 8)
  - Fundraising file
    - "Bridge to Finland" (Folder 9)
    - Lotta Svard (women's organization) (Box 235, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda (Folder 2-4)
  - Office file (Folder 5)
  - Reports (Folder 6)
  - Telegrams (Folder 7)
  - Volunteer file (Folder 8)
- Memorabilia, n.d (Box 236, 237-237A, 238)
  Buttons, coin boxes (including flat cardboard ones in Box 238), cotton banner, Finnish flags, miscellaneous material related to publicity, Herbert Hoover's and Raymond Sawtelle's facsimile stamp, pillow, pins. Includes wooden printing stamps (Box 237, 237A)
- Scrapbooks and Bound Volumes, 1939-1940
  Addresses, clippings, list of names, follow-up letters, biographies, posters relating mainly to activities of the American Scandinavian Division
  - General (Box 238)
  - American Scandinavian Division. Addresses, clippings, list of names, follow-up letters, biographies, posters, miscellany
    - General
    - Danish Division
    - Finnish Division
    - Norwegian Division
    - Swedish Division
  - Universities and colleges
- Printed Matter, 1933-1940 (Box 239, 239A)
  Bulletins, newsletters, serial issues and miscellany relating to FRF and Finland, particularly before and during World War II (in English and Finnish)
- Index Card File, undated
  Index cards relating to activities of the American Scandinavian Division, Labor Division, Sports Division, Motion Picture Division, and Women's Division
  - General (Box 240-242)
  - American Scandinavian Division (Box 243)
  - Labor Division (Box 244)
  - Sports Division (Box 245)
  - Motion Picture Division (Box 246)
  - Women's Division (Box 247)
- Photographs, 1939-1940
  584 prints, 3 negatives, 15 strips of negatives, 1 album of 14 prints, relating mostly to the Russo-Finnish War, 1939-1940
  - 1 print depicting Herbert Hoover; 1 print depicting Herbert Hoover with Perrin Galpin and Hendrik Willem van Loon; 1 print depicting Herbert Hoover with Maurice Pieters; 1 print depicting Herbert Hoover with unidentified person (Box 248, Folder A)
  - 18 prints depicting Finnish personalities involved in various relief activities, including Professor Cajander, Count Louis Sparre, Marcus and Karin Tollet, Aune Hanson Franks, Georg von Essen (Folder B)
  - 9 prints depicting Norwegian personalities, including Odd Nansen and Betzy Kjelsberg (Folder C)
  - 6 prints depicting Swedish personalities, including Folke Bernadotte, Gustav Lorentz Munthe, Alva Myrdal, Amandus Johnson, Elsa Brandstrom Ulrich (Folder D)
  - 1 print of a poster featuring American actress Helen Hayes asking for donations to the FRF (Folder E)
  - 69 prints depicting special events and fundraising campaign activities in the United States (Folder F-G)
  - 32 prints taken in Finland by Bob Maverick, FRF representative. Includes prints of the meeting in Suomen Huito between representatives of the Finnish Relief Fund, the Finland Fund of England and heads of the Government Medical Board of Finland, 1940 (Folder H)
  - 239 prints, 1940, taken by Frank Muto, FRF employee, depicting atrocities in various Finnish cities such as Tampere, Hango, Oulu, and in Lapland during the Russo-Finnish War, 1939-1940 (Folder I-V)
  - 20 prints depicting scenes of war destruction in Helsinki (Box 249, Folder W)
  - 22 prints depicting scenes on the Finnish front (Folder X)
  - 33 prints depicting Finnish refugees (Folder Y)
  - 35 prints depicting Finnish hospitals and war victims and invalids (Folder Z)
  - 40 prints depicting Finnish children (Folder AA)
  - 34 prints depicting the Finnish countryside (Folder AB)
  - 9 prints depicting Finnish workshops (Folder AC)
  - 4 prints depicting Finnish warehouses receiving aid from the FRF (Folder AD)
  - 8 prints depicting Lotta Svard, a Finnish women's volunteer organization (Folder AE)
  - 3 prints depicting the Forestry Institute of the University of Helsinki (Folder AF)
  - 1 print depicting Belgian soldiers (Folder AG)
  - 4 miscellany prints (Folder AH)
  - 1 album of 14 prints depicting Finnish self-supporting farms for families of fallen and wounded soldiers (Folder AI)
  - 3 negatives depicting Finnish refugees near Siiliujoki, Finland, and a meeting of a local district welfare committee (Folder AJ)
  - 15 strips of negatives of prints in the collection (Box 250)